MALAIKA RICHARDS

WEB DEVELOPER







in /malaikadev

I have studied Web Development and Design since 2012. I've worked in STEM since 2013. I graduated from the University of Central Florida in 2014 with a Digital Media BA concentrating on Web Design and a minor in Computer Science. While at UCF, I took every opportunity to exercise my development skills. I am a full-stack developer who has worked in Digital Marketing teams using CRMs, APIs, CMSs, and various frameworks. I volunteer my skills in my spare time.

TOP SKILLS

- HTML
- UI/UX
- CSS/SASS
- Adobe Suite
- JS/JQuery
- MS Suite
- AJAX
- Google Suite
- PHP
- Figma
- MySQL
- WordPress
- MS SQL
- Shopify/Twig
- Java
- Bootstrap
- Python
- Django
- C
- Hubspot
- CLI
- REST APIs
- Git
- IIS
- Gulp
- LAMP

EDUCATION

Digital Media, B.A. Web Design Concentration

Computer Science Minor

University of Central Florida / Orlando, FL

2015 - 2018

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

University of South Florida / Tampa, FL (Remote)

Aug 2022 - Present

I lead the Tech team for the Office of Strategic Enrollment Management and Operations. We assist the marketing department in creating and maintaining our web-based assets and facilitate the work of our campus partners. We are also helping the university transition to a new CRM that will consolidate multiple tools and improve the applicant experience.

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

University of South Florida / Tampa, FL (Remote) May 2020 - Aug 2022

I generated landing pages, websites, emails, and templates for these assets. I established marketing automation pipelines with lead generation tools and market segmentation. I worked alongside numerous campus partners with my interdisciplinary team to spearhead the introduction of new technologies across campus. We used APIs to facilitate data reconciliation through MS SQL, HubSpot, Talisma, Banner, and our campus partners.

WEB DEVELOPER

Big Sea / Saint Petersburg, FL (Hybird Remote)

Jan 2019 - May 2020

I launched six websites while maintaining 15 websites with my team through WordPress, Hubspot, and Shopify. I developed innovative solutions for our clients through unique plugins and APIs, some of which we developed. I created stunning interactions with SASS and JS animations to grab the audience's attention.

WEB DESIGNER

Citizen Science GIS / Orlando, FL

Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

I redesigned and developed their WordPress website by creating a custom theme from scratch. I helped realign the organization's brand to its message by creating a personalized design language. I found their voice as an entity and maintained their site.